Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
We're detecting a high energy reaction
from inside the target!
What?!
The circumference area is accelerating!
It's converging!
It can't be!
No, dodge it!
Retrieve him, hurry!
The target has gone silent!
How's Shinji?
He's alive!
Unit 01 has been recovered.
En route to the 7th cage.
I'm going to the cage.
Take over for me, please!
Unit 01 secured!
Hurry with the cooling!
The pilot's brain waves are erratic!
His pulse is very weak.
Increase life support to maximum power.
Give him a heart massage.
Yes, Ma'am!
Pulse confirmed!
Force eject the entry plug! Hurry!
Emergency LCL discharge!
Yes, Ma'am!
Come on, open the hatch! Hurry!
Shinji!
EPISODE SIX
DECISIVE BATTLE,
NEW TOKYO-3
1/1 Scale Balloon Dummy
The enemy's particle beam cannon has hit!
The dummy has been vaporized!
Next.
Automated Model 12 Self-Propelled Mortar
The Model 12 Self-Propelled Mortar
has been destroyed!
I see.
From the data we've collected,
we're assuming that the target
automatically attacks any opponent
within a certain range.
The likelihood of it hitting anything entering
the area with its particle beam is 100%.
Department of Operations, Nerv Headquarters
Analysis Room 2
It's too risky for close range combat
in an Eva, isn't it?
What about its AT field?
It's still active.
REPLAY IMAGE
It's strong enough that the spatial changes
in phase are visible to the naked eye.
Using half-measures like guided missiles,
artillery, or bombs
will inflict more damage on us
than on the Angel!
Offensively and defensively it's
almost perfect. A flying fortress.
What's the status on its drill?
At this moment the target
is directly above us,
penetrating the New Tokyo-3 Null Zone.
A giant shielded drill with
a diameter of 17.5 meters
is boring towards Nerv HQ.
The enemy is planning to attack Nerv
Headquarters directly.
Sassy bastard!
So, what's its ETA?
Japan Standard Time
Remaining Estimated Time
12:06:54 AM.
By that time, it will have breached
all twenty-two levels of armor,
APPROXIMATED
GRAPHICS
and arrive at Nerv Headquarters itself.
Less than ten hours...
PRESENT TIME
The drill has contacted the first armor plate.
What's the condition of Unit 01?
The defensive armor was melted
down to the third layer.
Cage 7, Nerv Headquarters
The silver lining is that the central
control unit sustained no damage.
Three more seconds, and
it would have been over.
In three hours, the replacement parts
should be installed.
Roger.
What's the status of Unit 00?
Re-activation itself should
prove no problem,
but there's still a feedback error.
So actual combat...
...is still impossible.
What's the condition of Unit 01's pilot?
Emergency Room, Central Hospital,
Nerv Headquarters
No physical damage.
However, his nerve pulses are up by 0.8.
Still within acceptable limits.
Enemy drill arrival: 9 hours, 55 minutes.
The situation certainly isn't favorable.
Shall we just raise a white flag?
Before we resort to that,
there's one little thing I'd like to try.
You want a sniper to shoot the target
from outside its firing zone?
Nerv Commander's Office
Yes, Sir.
Instead of trying to neutralize
the target's AT field,
I believe a pinpoint shot with a
high-energy beam is the only way.
What do the Magi say?
The responses from the Magi
Super Computers
were two affirmative and
one conditional affirmative.
So, our probability of success is 8.7 percent.
It's quite a high percentage.
I see no reason to raise an objection.
You may proceed, Captain Katsuragi.
Yes, Sir.
But you sure have come up with
a reckless plan,
Operations Director Katsuragi.
Don't be rude. It's not reckless!
It can be executed within the
nine hours we have left,
and has the highest chance of success.
This thing does? Really?
Eva Positron Rifle
(Prototype 20 with Toroidal Accelerator)
But our positron rifle can't handle
such a high output.
What are you going to do about that?
We'll borrow one, of course.
Borrow one? You don't mean...
Right! The Strategic SDF Lab's prototype!
Requisition Order
Nerv is hereby requisitioning this
Self Propelled Positron Cannon
as of 15:00 today.
Tsukuba Technology Laboratory Headquarters, Strategic SDF
But still, this is ridiculous!
Special Units Hangar 4
We'll try to return this in as close
to its original condition as we can.
We appreciate your cooperation!
Okay, Rei! Take it away!
That's a piece of precision machinery,
so be careful!
Even so, our calculations
show that it will take
at least 180 million kilowatts to
penetrate that AT field.
Where are you going to get
that much electricity?
Where else? From all of Japan!
Giant Power Outage Today All Across Japan
We apologize for interrupting
our regular programming for this
Emergency Bulletin.
Suzuhara Residence
From 11:30 PM tonight
until tomorrow morning,
Horaki Residence
New Tokyo-2
there will be a large scale power blackout
throughout most of Japan.
New Makurazaki, Kagoshima Prefecture
We appreciate your cooperation.
Repeat, from 11:30 PM tonight
until tomorrow morning
At dawn today,
a large-scale
power outage
all across the nation.
Betsukai, Hokkaido
Ube, Yamaguchi Prefecture
there will be a large scale power
blackout throughout Japan.
We appreciate your cooperation.
Mitaka Ward, Old Tokyo
New Tokyo-3
Control Room, General Operations
Command Center, Nerv Headquarters
The drill has just broken through
the seventh defensive layer.
What's the status on our energy system?
New Odawara, Kanagawa Prefecture
3.2% behind schedule, but we should
manage to be finished by 23:10.
And the positron rifle?
On the honor of Technology
Development Department 3,
Technology Department Division 3, Nerv Headquarters
(In charge of electromagnetic and light wave hardware)
we'll have it built for you in three hours.
What about our defensive measures?
Well, using a shield is about all we can do.
Hangar 8, Nerv Headquarters
Eva Anti-Heat and Light Wave Defensive Equipment
(Makeshift Specs)
So, this is the shield?
Yes. It's a hand-me-down from
a single stage to orbit rocket.
It may look ugly, but it's got a super-
electromagnetic base coating that
Section 2 guarantees will stand up to
the enemy's particle beam
for at least seventeen seconds.
Good. Have you determined
the sniper position?
Given the range to the target,
geographical features,
and taking power access into consideration,
this would be the spot.
Definitely looks good.
The sniping position will be atop Mt. Futago!
The operation will commence
at 00:00 tomorrow morning!
From this point on, this operation will be
called "Operation Yashima".
Roger.
Now, the only remaining problem
is the pilot.
Unit 01's designated pilot is conscious now.
Cage 7 Control Room
His examination results look normal.
Good. Then, the operation will
proceed as planned.
Roger.
But I wonder if he'll pilot it again.
Get ready for a decisive battle at Mt. Futago!
Surgical Ward 3, Central Hospital
Ayanami...
I'm here to brief you on the timetable
of Operation Yashima,
which will begin tomorrow at 00:00 hours.
Pilots Ikari and Ayanami will arrive
at the cage at 17:30 today.
At 18:00, Units 01 and 00 will activate.
Launch is at 18:05.
They will arrive at the temporary base
on Mt. Futago at 18:30.
There, they will stand by and
await further orders.
The operation will begin
promptly at midnight.
Here's a new one.
Don't show up half-asleep looking like that.
Sorry.
All I've been doing since
yesterday is apologizing.
Your meal.
I don't want to eat anything.
We'll be departing in sixty minutes.
Do I have to pilot that thing again?
Yes, you do.
I don't want to.
Maybe you can be so cool about it,
because you haven't had the kind
of experiences I've had yet.
I don't want to go through that again.
Then why don't you stay in bed?
Stay in bed?
I'll pilot Unit 01.
Dr. Akagi is already prepared to rewrite
Unit 01's personal data files.
Miss Ritsuko is...
I'm leaving. Captain Katsuragi and
Dr. Akagi will be waiting at the cage.
Goodbye.
No School Today
New Tokyo-3 Public Middle School 1 Principal
They're awfully late. We oughta
evacuate to the shelter.
I hacked into my dad's data files.
I'm sure this is the time.
Yeah, but they still ain't here.
The mountain is moving.
The Evangelions!
Cool!
Go for it! We're counting on you!
Evangelion! Good luck!
8:11 PM
Near Asahi Falls on Mt. Futago
The drill has penetrated through
the 17th layer of armor.
It will reach headquarters in
3 hours 55 minutes.
No problem with the hub
synchronization system.
Power supply transfer from Shikoku
and Kyushu is completed.
Begin tests of each cooling system.
This is a piece of precision machinery,
so handle it carefully.
Eva Positron Sniper Rifle
(Nerv Specs - Formerly Strategic SDF Lab's Automated Positron Rifle)
This thing wasn't built for field operations.
Will it really work?
There's no choice.
This is a makeshift solution.
So it'll be okay?
Theoretically, yes.
However, we won't know if the cannon barrel
and accelerator will hold until we try firing it.
This is the first time it's been fired
with such a high power output.
Here are your individual duties
for the operation.
Shinji...
Yes, Ma'am.
Your Unit 01 will be the gunner.
Rei, you're in charge of defense with Unit 00.
Yes, Ma'am.
This is because Shinji has a higher
sync ratio with Unit 01,
and this operation will require
exceptional precision.
Since the positron beam will be
influenced by the Earth's gravity,
magnetic fields and rotation,
it will not fire in a straight line.
You must remember to make
adjustments for these deviations.
You must penetrate the core precisely.
But I've never practiced this!
Don't worry.
Just do what the manual says.
When the indicators converge
in the center, pull the trigger.
The computers will handle the rest.
Also, once you fire it,
it will take time before you can fire again
for cooling, reloading,
and replacement of the fuses.
Then, if I miss and the enemy shoots back...
Don't think about unnecessary
things right now.
Just think about destroying it in one shot.
So it's crisis time.
I...
I just need to defend Unit 01, correct?
That's right.
Understood.
It's time. Both of you, get changed.
Yes, Ma'am.
We might die doing this.
Why do you say that?
You won't die.
Because I'll protect you.
...a large-scale power outage all across...
Why do you pilot this thing?
Because I'm bound.
Bound?
Yes, it's a bond.
With my father?
With all people.
You're very strong, Ayanami.
Because I have nothing else.
What do you mean, "you have nothing else"?
It's time. Let's go.
Goodbye.
The time is now 00:00:00.
Type 14 Large Mobile Command Car
Japan Standard Time
Commencing operation.
Inside Command Car
Shinji, we're entrusting you with
all the electricity of Japan.
Good luck.
Yes, Ma'am!
Initiate primary connection.
Initiating power transmission from
districts number 1 through 803.
Number 1 transmission system nominal.
No problem with hub synchronizer output.
All transmission induction systems activated.
Conversion efficiency staying
within estimated values.
Voltage is rising. Reaching pressure zone.
All cooling systems, full power!
Electron condenser system nominal.
Auxiliary system activated.
Temperature stable. No problems detected.
Positron charge is nominal.
Initiate secondary connection!
All accelerators engaging.
Activate convergence unit.
Transmitting all power to Mt. Futago
temporary substation.
No problems reported
with tertiary connection.
Release final safety systems.
Clear the chamber!
Safe Empty
Armed
Loaded
Error correction for Earth rotation
and gravity is plus 0.0009.
Voltage is 0.2 short of critical.
Seventh and final connection engaged!
All photo-electron fuses,
commence convergence!
Transmitting all energy to the positron rifle!
8...
7...
6...
5...
High energy output detected from the target!
4...
3...
What did you say?
2...
1...
Fire!
We missed?
The enemy drill has broken
into the Geo-Front!
Fire two! Hurry!
Replacing fuses! Initiating recharge!
Barrel cooling in progress!
Resume positron acceleration!
Another high energy reading
coming from the target!
Oh, no!
Shinji!
Ayanami!
The shield won't last!
Aren't we ready yet?!
Ten more seconds!
Hurry up!
Yes!
Ayanami!
Are you all right?!
Don't say... Don't say that
you have nothing else.
Don't say goodbye when you leave
on a mission. It's too sad.
Why are you crying?
I'm sorry. I don't know what to do
at a time like this.
You can just smile.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
The humanoid weapon
that the civilans developed
to fight against the encroaching Angels
goes out of control.
Will Misato be able to stop the meltdown?
It's the next episode:
"That Which is Manmade"
Look forward to it!
THAT WHICH IS MANMADE